ABDUL AZIZ SHAIKH

LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR



+91 7738692054



shaikhabdul555@gmail.com



Mumbai, India



https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-aziz-shaikh-69a86215b/

Objective

As an IT Infrastructure Specialist having 4 years of experiences, Worked with HP and Sun server as Engineer & System Admin in a team of 40 members. Performed RHEL Linux & RHEV system administration tasks like installation and configuration of software components and services, Monitoring and managing processes.

Experience

Employer - DXC Technology (Sep 2022 - Till Now). Sify DATA Center (Rabale) Navi Mumbai, India

Client: (IPPB) Indian Post Payment Bank Role- Professional System Administrator

Team Size: 40

- Installation, Configuration, Administration and Upgrade of Redhat Linux 7.9 Operating systems.
- Providing L2 Support for all issues includes day to day system administration tasks monitoring, troubleshooting, system performance tuning.
- Build and OS patch update of Linux servers using Red Hat Satellite DC DR NDR and Non-Prod.
- Responding to **SM Tools** generated incident-tickets.
- Monitoring and optimizing system performance and reliability. Maintaining a scheduled process through CRON.
- Configuring the LVM (Logical Volume Manager) and extended the logical volumes online.
- Worked on securing data by using permission policies, User & Group Administration.
- Exposure to Linux with various services like NFS
- Configure access control using IP tables, access, host deny & host allow.
- Privileges to Finacle and DB users.
- Configuration of Remote Access utilities, providing user access control on services like telnet, ftp and SSH.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and repair system related problems.
- DR Drill Activity.

Employer - Fidelis Corporate Solution Ltd (Mar 2022 - Sep 2022).

Sify DATA Center (Rabale) Navi Mumbai, India

Client: DXC Technology, IPPB

Role- Linux Admin Team Size: 40

- Installation, Configuration, Administration and Upgrade of Redhat Linux 7.9 Operating systems.
- Providing L2 Support for all issues includes day to day system administration tasks monitoring, troubleshooting, system performance tuning.
- Build and OS patch update of Linux servers using Red Hat Satellite DC DR NDR and Non-Prod.
- Responding to SM Tools generated incident-tickets.
- Monitoring and optimizing system performance and reliability. Maintaining a scheduled process through CRON.
- Configuring the LVM (Logical Volume Manager) and extended the logical volumes online.
- Worked on securing data by using permission policies, User & Group Administration.
- Exposure to Linux with various services like NFS
- Configure access control using IP tables, access, host deny & host allow.
- Privileges to Finacle and DB users.
- Configuration of Remote Access utilities, providing user access control on services like telnet, ftp and SSH.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and repair system related problems.
- DR Drill Activity.

Employer - InspiriSYS Solutions Ltd (Mar 2021 - Mar 2022).

SCI DATA Center (Powai) Mumbai, India Client: Shipping Corporation of India

Role- Engineer - System Admin

Team Size: 20

- Mailing and telephonic support to organization.
- Remote assist to resolve problems.
- Responding to the Veritas Netbackup Tools issue.
- Discussing client requirements and advice accordingly.
- Handling calls with client as per log of servers on daily basis.
- Check Production Servers Log. Create & manage lym's.
- Monitoring Netbackup Tools
- Monitoring Tickets
- Run database Script as per client request.
- Monitoring all Linux Servers
- File sharing with NFS, and FTP
- Copy FMX file in production server as per client request.
- Change ownership of file and change permission on file system for owner, group and other
- Configure Local Repository
- Add Cron as per Client request.
- Schedule backups and creating new policies.

Employer - Sysnet Global Technologies (May 2018 - Feb 2020).

Sify DATA Center (Rabale) Navi Mumbai, India

Client: DXC Technology, IPPB Role- Linux Support Engineer/DCO

Team Size: 40

- Using Service Manager Tools Monitoring Linux servers such as Disk space utilization, CPU utilization, Memory utilization (TOP, vmstat, iostat, free, prstat)
- Setup desktop computers and peripherals and test network connections.
- Monitoring SM, OMI and RHEV tools DC and DR sides.
- Monitoring DC and DR Health check monitor IPPB Critical DC-DRPing and Resource Utilization Report Linux.
- Logging more than 40 middleware servers by script on daily basis.
- Create incident assign and closed of Wintel DB Unix Solaris and Middleware tickets.
- Everyday Dashboard reports sent to the bank at 11:00 AM.
- Remote assist to resolve problems.
- Responding to the backup issue raised by L1 /Bank Team.
- Checked CPU, Memory and file system issue high utilization.
- Handling calls with client as per log of servers on daily basis.
- Responding Patching activity when approved from Bank.

Skill Set

Linux Administration Skills:

- Installation, Configuration, and Troubleshooting of OS'sRHEL, CentOS, Windows
- User Administration
- Understanding Linux File System
- Symlinks & Hardlinks
- Archiving & Compression
- File Permissions
- Basics of Shell Scripting
- Troubleshooting of system booting level error (Maintenance Mode or Kernel Panic)
- Linux Schedulers(CRON)
- Disk and Quota Management
- Software and Packages installation using YUM, RPM

Veritas Netbackup Tools Skills:-

- 1) Monitoring backups
- 2) Creating Policies
- 3) Insert and Eject Media (Weekly and Monthly).
- 4) Restore backup
- 5) Expire Media

Education

B.Sc.IT(Information Technology)

Mumbai University

(2010-2014)

Certifications

• Done AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate & Redhat Linux Certification

Validation No: CXKKD8F1Y1VQQQ3Y

• Certification ID: 190-311-084

Declaration

I do here by declare that the particulars of information and facts stated here in above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

DATE:

PLACE: Mumbai Abdul Aziz Shaikh